Jeziel Lopes Carvalho

Ipatinga, MG



jeziellcarvalho@gmail.com



31993841675



linkedin.com/in/jezielcarvalho



https://jeziellopes.github.io

Summary

MITx 6.00x certified. BS in Information Systems. As a graduated Software Engineer, I seek to acquire and improve skills involving the entire life cycle of web applications. Working with agile, requirements engineering, infra and code architecture, data modeling and persistence, services integrations, and user experience applied to user interface development, always thinking about problem-solving, and delivering value with web and mobile user experience.

Communication and language:

- English: Advanced programming in English (official docs and articles reading, Ubiquitous Language (DDD) applied to coding, good speech understanding, conversation levels need to be worked on.

Academic Foundations:

- Software Engineering, FP, OOP, TDD, DDD
- MVC, Repository Pattern
- SOLID, KISS, DRY, Clean Code, YAGNI
- SCRUM, Kanban

Experience



🖘 Full Stack Engineer

DevSkin - Outsourcina

Dec 2021 - Jun 2022 (7 months)

JavaScript | TypeScript | Node.js | React | Serverless | AWS Lambdas | Amazon SQS

Responsabilities:

- RESTful APIs (Service-oriented Architecture, Repository Pattern, Swagger)
- Automations using AWS Lambdas (Serverless, MongoDB)
- Componentizing (HOCs, Containers, Contexts, Components, Styled-Components)
- Context API (separação e unificação de contextos, no prop drilling).
- React Hooks (useEffect, useContext, useMemo, useCallback, useRef, ...)
- Local Storage and Cookies (expires, maxAge, httpOnly, ...)
- API Integrations (AxiosError, AbortController, Interceptors, ...)
- Unit Tests e Integration Tests (Jest, React Testing Library)
- SOLID, KISS, DRY, Clean Code, YAGNI



Senior Front End React

ioasys

May 2021 - Dec 2021 (8 months)

TypeScript | React.js | Gatsby | Nextjs | Storybook | Nexus/NPM | Bitbucket Pipelines | AWS

Responsibilities:

- Flux Architecture (Redux, Redux Sagas) and Context API.
- Landing Pages (Gatsby e Nextjs) with authentication.
- Semantic HTML5 (Header, Body, Section, Article, Footer)
- CSS3 (Animations, Transitions, Shadows, Flexbox, Grid)
- Session Storage, Local Storage, and Cookies.
- Axios (Error handling e interceptors).
- Components and Styles (Styled-Components, Material IU)
- Unit Tests e Integration Tests (Jest, React Testing Library)
- Design System (NPM, Nexus) and Storybook (Controls)
- DevOps (Bitbucket Pipelines, AWS CloudFront)
- SCRUM, Kanban

녜 React Native | Flutter Developer

Foodway

Apr 2020 - Mar 2021 (1 year)

React Native | Flutter | App Stores Apple/Google

Development of new MVP features, using React Native. Among the assignments in the project are: modularization and styling using Styled Components; from integration with external APIs, through managing information in the Redux global state of the application, to testing and validation of user experience flow.

Full Stack JS | UI Developer

Plus.me Agência Criativa

Nov 2019 - Apr 2020 (6 months)

Figma | ReactJS | Nodejs/AdonisJS | Docker | SaaS

Development of dashboards and landing pages for marketing campaigns with React and Styled-Components, with AdonisJS on the backend.

Full Stack Lavavel | PHP | JS Developer

Grupo Central | Central Farma e Central Nutrition

Feb 2019 - Nov 2019 (10 months)

JavaScript | MySQL | PHP | Laravel | AWS

Modeling, implementations, cron jobs, API integrations, Laravel MVC for the backend, and front-end with ES5, jQuery, and CSS.

Education



Centro Universitário do Leste de Minas Gerais

Sistemas de Informação, Análise de Sistemas

2017 - 2021

Senac Minas

Técnico em Redes de Computadores, Informática 2009 - 2011

Licenses & Certifications

мітх 6.00x: Introduction to Computer Science and Programming using Python - MITx on edX

f8f11acdec7e4453be6ef75e20638afd

Skills

React.js • Node.js • TypeScript • MongoDB • JavaScript • React Native • Flutter • Amazon SQS • Serverless Computing • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)